

# **BEN FOK**

#### FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER | SENIOR LEADER | PROFESSIONAL COACH

Full Stack Web Developer blending technical skillset with over a decade of operational, people and leadership experience as an elite level educator and senior leader at a Fortune 1000 company. This positions Ben uniquely as a creative engineer who understands the role and the strategic impact of technology across all facets of the business, and one who can speak both the language of the web and that of your team to drive results.

benfok8@gmail.com



(530)314-1419



Leavenworth, WA



benfok.github.io/portfolio1



github.com/benfok



linkedin.com/in/benfok

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML5

**JavaScript** 

Node.is

ReactJS

iQuerv Git

Handlebars

MongoDB

Express

RESTful APIs

MS 365 and Office

Adobe Workfront

Articulate 360

"I have done some of my most enjoyable and mentally stimulating work with Ben" -Senior coworker

"I find Ben inspiring because he just comes up with good stuff! No BS, just accuracy in content and attention to detail which is great!" -Senior coworker

"Ben finds the potential in others and creates space for them the thrive. He is genuine and leads with kindness" -Former employee

# INTERESTS











## **EXPERIENCE**

### CEO | TIDY LINES LLC

November 2021 - Present | Leavenworth, WA

- o Freelance web development, copy writing, project management and consulting.
- o Currently contracted by Vail Resorts; a Fortune 1000 company. Project, content and contractor management across 34 websites.
- Improved workflow efficiency and reduced issue resolution time by over 30%
- o Project Lead for digital content execution for product launch in Match '22 and content migration for 3 new acquisitions beginning June '22.
- o Former consulting clients include Mt Hood Meadows, OR and Mountain High Resort, CA.
- o Coding examples can be found through my GitHub profile

#### Director of Skier Services | Stevens Pass, Vail Resorts

October 2013 - November 2021 | Leavenworth, WA

- Director of operations for departments totaling 400+ employees and over \$4M in direct revenue. Doubled revenue in a 5-year period prior to COVID-19.
- Project manager and SME on development of an industry leading custom ecommerce platform (in 2016-2017) handing \$6M+ annual revenue.
- Created a deployed a critical thinking model companywide (40K employees) to improve decision making and reduce work safety incidents by up to 75%.
- Designed and executed leadership training and employee orientation for all resort staff (800+) and management annually.
- o Recognized nationally for my leadership skills and business impact.

[SNOW Operating Platinum Award Winner 2017 | NSAA Conversion Cup Runner up 2016, 2017 and 2018 | Vail Resorts Camp II graduate in 2021 | Member of NSAA Growth Committee | Former consulting clients include Mt Hood Meadows Ski Resort, OR and Mtn High Resort, CA]

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Full Stack Web Development - Certificate**

University of Washington – Graduating May 2022

JavaScript, Asynchronous JavaScript and Node.js Codecademy.com

Full Cert Ski Instructor & former Northwest Technical Team Member

Professional Ski Instructors of America – Since 2006

#### **Business, Physics and Statistics**

Chepstow Comprehensive, Wales U.K - 1997-2003